ISAAC MILLS-OWOO

ikejrmillsowoo@gmail.com | https://github.com/lkejrmillsowoo | <u>www.linkedin.com/in/isaac-mills-owoo</u> | www.imillsowoo.com Bear, DE.

Professional Summary

Highly skilled Frontend Developer with experience in React and other JavaScript, CSS and HTML frameworks with over 10 years in leadership, management and as a Registered Respiratory Therapist. Experienced with training, onboarding, and educating other members team members, looking for an opportunity as a Frontend Web developer in a role that provides an opportunity to learn, grow and mentor.

Technical Skills

- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript/jQuery
- Bootstrap
- React
- React Native

- Node.js
- Git
- GitHub
- Command Line
- MS Office Suite
- EMAR

Technical Certifications

HTML; CSS; JavaScript; React; Git - CodeAcademy

- Learned basic object-oriented concepts using the latest JavaScript syntax, while learning programming fundamentals.
- Gained the skills to ensure websites remain legible and visually appealing across a variety of devices and platforms.
- Utilized responsive design techniques to increase website accessibility to reach a much larger audience of users.

HTML; CSS; JavaScript/jQuery; Bootstrap; React; React Native; Node.js; Git; GitHub – NuCamp Frontend Web Developer Cert.

- Learned to build websites that can be developed for all screen sizes, including addressing responsive design and grids.
- Explored React, a JavaScript library, and covered advanced aspects of JavaScript ES6 and React components like redux.
- Utilized React Native and Expo SDK to access all native hardware capabilities of modern phones and tablets.
- Joined teams and contributed to projects, leveraging the version control system Git to track all changes being made.

AWS Cloud Practitioner Certification - Amazon Web Services

- Defined basic global infrastructure and understood key services and use cases, including computing and analytics.
- Addressed account management, pricing models, and core characteristics of deploying and operating in the AWS Cloud.
- Effectively learned to make decisions based on architectural principles while identifying and solving configuration issues.
- Designed architectures to decouple infrastructure and reduce interdependencies, and automated resource deployment.

Education

Wilmington University -2021

Master of Science in Information Systems Technologies & Internet/Web Design

- Gained skills to manage complex systems and coordinate relationships between business requirements and solutions.
- Explored Web Design and Development with JavaScript, HTML, Visual Basic, as well as advanced multimedia and animation.
- Applied models for planning, organizing, designing, managing, and implementing IS within modern organizations.
- Understanding the importance of managing risks related to processes and policies in web infrastructure.

Wilmington University – 2020

Master of Business Administration in Management Information Systems

- Covered project, change, data management and analysis, along with modeling, design, data comms, and networking.
- Learned systems development life cycle, analysis, and design techniques along with IS systems planning methods.
- Studied standards and security for design, implementation, and management of digital networks, and LAN and WAN.
- Covered project initiation, planning, integration, scope, time, cost, quality control, risk management, and reporting.

Wilmington University, New Castle, DE – 2011

Bachelor of Science in Allied Health Education

Delaware Technical & Community College, Newark, DE - 2009

Associate of Science in Respiratory Therapy

General Skills

- Responsive & User-Centric Design
- Project Scope, Scheduling & Management
- Structuring Code & Data
- Risk & Quality Management

- Managing & Mentoring Employees
- Problem-Solving & Collaboration Skills
- Attention to Detail & Ensuring Accuracy
- Excellent Verbal & Written Communication

Projects

- Access Health React/ react strap health information based responsive web page.
- Foodies App Using React/ Yelp API to create a business search app
- Tip Calculator- Simple calculator that split the bill evenly among users.

Professional Experience

Supervisor, Epic EMAR Transition Manager & Registered Respiratory Therapist – Good Shepherd Penn Partners – 2013 to Present

Respiratory Therapist – Jennersville Regional Hospital – 2017 to Present

Registered Respiratory Care Manager – Nemours Children's Hospital – 2010 to 2019

Registered Respiratory Therapist – Select Specialty Hospitals – 2011 to 2017

Professional Affiliations & Activities

Member – American Association of Respiratory Care – 2009 to Present

Member – Delaware Association of Respiratory Care – 2009 to Present

Member - Delaware Association of Respiratory Care - 2011 to Present

Member – National Board of Respiratory Care – 2009 to Present